<books>
  <book number="1">
    <dates>
      <start>6/30/1982</start>
      <end>11/17/1982</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This is the earliest sketchbook found in the archive and is a landscape orientation. The sketchbook has drawings from Keith teaching at the summer program Parsons Paris and drawings from the Long weekend cottage in Pine Bush, NY.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="2">
    <dates>
      <start>7/1/1983</start>
      <end>7/24/1983</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is only drawings from Keith’s time teaching at Parsons Paris during the summer of 1983.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="3">
    <dates>
      <start>7/30/83</start>
      <end>8/10/83</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is a landscape orientation. Journal entries and sketches are from drawing classes for Parsons in Paris.  This book has many drawings from student outings to cave painting sites around France.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="4">
    <dates>
      <start>6/9/83</start>
      <end>8/15/84</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has no journal entries, only sketches. There are sketches of family, friends, landscapes, and airports.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="5">
    <dates>
      <start>8/2/83</start>
      <end>8/23/84</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is square shaped. Only the first few pages are used and are of ink washed drawings of Paris and Barcelona.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="6">
    <dates>
      <start>6/29/84</start>
      <end>8/18/84</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is from the summer of 1984 while Keith continued to teach at the Parsons Paris program. It’s mostly drawings but does have several journal entries. Many drawings are from cave painting sites in France.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="7">
    <dates>
      <start>6/27/85</start>
      <end>8/15/85</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is from summer 1985 and documents Keith’s time teaching at Parsons Paris summer program. The sketchbook consists mostly of visits to cave drawing sites in France. There are also drawings from a trip to London.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="8">
    <dates>
      <start>5/31/86</start>
      <end>8/7/86</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook documents Keith’s time at jury duty in June 1986. It also has sketches and journal entries from a trip to Italy (Pisa, Siena, Rome, Orvieto, Florence). A few additional drawings at the end of the sketchbook are from a trip to Eastern Pennsylvania.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="9">
    <dates>
      <start>10/14/86</start>
      <end>11/12/86</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is mostly journal entries and sketches from a trip through Nepal that Keith went on with friends.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="10">
    <dates>
      <start>6/27/87</start>
      <end>8/14/87</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook documents the summer of 1987 in Paris. There are many sketches of time spent with friends as well as more visits to cave painting sites throughout France.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="11">
    <dates>
      <start>8/14/87</start>
      <end>1/30/88</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is mostly of drawings that follow Keith and Ruth through Paris, Amsterdam, Dijon, and Egypt.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="12">
    <dates>
      <start>2/12/88</start>
      <end>6/30/88</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is mostly drawings documenting Keith’s time in Paris, at Hogan’s Graduation and the Minneapolis Zoo in MN, and travels to Greece.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="13">
    <dates>
      <start>7/1/88</start>
      <end>6/19/89</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook documents another summer in Paris, a trip to California, and sketches from Macy’s Thanksgiving Parade in NYC. The final entries are from Pine Bush and a drawing from a visit to Maine.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="14">
    <dates>
      <start>6/30/89</start>
      <end>8/6/89</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has journal entries and sketches from summer of 1989 in Paris. Keith is still teaching for Parsons in Paris.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="15">
    <dates>
      <start>6/29/90</start>
      <end>9/16/90</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has journal entries and sketches from the summer of 1990 in Paris. Keith is still teaching for Parsons in Paris.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="16">
    <dates>
      <start>10/29/90</start>
      <end>2/2/91</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is mostly journal entries and only has a few sketches. Many journal entries discuss Keith’s dreams. A few entries discuss plans for new wall sculptures.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="17">
    <dates>
      <start>2/6/91</start>
      <end>6/29/91</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is mostly journal entries and a few sketches. The journal's entries discuss dreams, teaching at Parsons, and studio work. A few sketches from jury duty in May of 1991.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="18">
    <dates>
      <start>6/29/91</start>
      <end>8/7/91</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has both journal entries and sketches from the summer of 1991 in Paris. Keith visits and makes drawings from many cave painting sites throughout France.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="19">
    <dates>
      <start>8/8/91</start>
      <end>1/10/92</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>Keith becomes director of Parsons Paris. This sketchbook is mostly journal entries. The final entries are sketches of Keith and Ruth’s travels through Kenya.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="20">
    <dates>
      <start>2/15/92</start>
      <end>7/2/92</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This journal follows Keith through winter travels in Italy with Ruth and then time spent in Paris. Later entries document a trip through Ukraine, Latvia, and Russia.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="21">
    <dates>
      <start>7/8/92</start>
      <end>7/30/93</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is mostly of Keith’s time in Paris and traveling around France as well as a trip to Strasbourg. It has both journal entries and sketches. There is a large pause in the sketchbook and most entries are from July 1992 and then July 1993.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="22">
    <dates>
      <start>9/3/93</start>
      <end>6/23/95</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook documents times in both Paris and New York. There are several landscape sketches using watercolor.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="23">
    <dates>
      <start>6/24/95</start>
      <end>7/17/95</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook documents the summer of 1995 and Keith’s and Ruth’s time in Paris and Marseille</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="24">
    <dates>
      <start>9/2/95</start>
      <end>11/20/96</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook documents time spent in Pine Bush and a trip to Morocco.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="25">
    <dates>
      <start>3/16/96</start>
      <end>5/18/97</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>
      <p>This sketchbook documents a Spring Break trip to Paris with students from Parsons. There is also a series of drawings from the Winter Garden in New York where they are installing for the annual Orchard Show.</p>
      <p>Later journal entries and drawings show a trip to Amsterdam, Prague, and Paris in May. In June, Ruth and Keith return to New York where Keith documents animals at the Bronx Zoo and people at Jackson Square and Union Square in NYC.</p>
      <p>This sketchbook has many journal entries that are describing Keith’s dreams.</p>
    </comment>
  </book>

  <book number="26">
    <dates>
      <start>6/17/97</start>
      <end>11/27/97</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>
      <p>This sketchbook documents Keith’s trip with Ruth to Peru for his show at the ICPNA in Lima. After the opening at ICPNA the sketchbook documents Keith and Ruth’s travels around other cities and locations in Peru.</p>
      <p>The sketchbook jumps from the end of their trip to Peru in July 1997 to sketches of Macy’s Thanksgiving Day Parade in November 1997.</p>
    </comment>
  </book>

  <book number="27">
    <dates>
      <start>1/5/98</start>
      <end>7/24/98</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook documents Keith and Ruth’s time in their homes in Paris and Pine Bush. There are few drawings from Union Square in NYC and many from a trip to Mongolia and more specifically of the Nadam Festival they attended on their travels. The Nadam Festival is Mongolia’s largest national holiday and features competitions in Mongolian wrestling, archery, and long-distance horse racing.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="28">
    <dates>
      <start>10/22/98</start>
      <end>6/26/02</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has drawings from time spent in New Orleans, Paris, and Amsterdam. There are also drawings from the Thanksgiving Day Parade in NYC.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="29">
    <dates>
      <start>11/4/02</start>
      <end>4/13/06</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has drawings from time spent in Russia, Long Island, Paris, Pine Bush, and NYC.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="30">
    <dates>
      <start>6/1/06</start>
      <end>6/31/07</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook mostly has drawings from Paris and a trip to Venice.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="31">
    <dates>
      <start>7/7/07</start>
      <end>11/29/07</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has many drawings of a tree removal in Pine Bush. There are also drawings from Paris and Spain.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="32">
    <dates>
      <start>11/30/08</start>
      <end>9/28/11</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is mostly journal entries and sketches from Paris. There are a lot of drawings from Père-Lachaise Cemetery.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="33">
    <dates>
      <start>9/28/11</start>
      <end>5/17/14</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has many drawings of the Père-Lachaise Cemetery and a Fêtes de Musique celebration at the Cluny Museum in Paris. There are also many journal entries in this book that discuss the upcoming presidential election, exhibition preparations, and family and friends. There are also several sketches of a tree removal.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="34">
    <dates>
      <start>5/25/14</start>
      <end>1/30/16</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook is mostly entries from Paris with many sketches of the Père-Lachaise Cemetery. It also documents the Fêtes de Musique in Paris as well as some airport drawings. The sketchbook also documents a quick trip to Switzerland taken in order to not run over their VISA in France.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="35">
    <dates>
      <start>5/7/16</start>
      <end>8/2/16</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This is a soft cover journal and one of the shorter journals Keith kept. It has a few drawings of Pine Bush and churches. In many of the journal entries Keith writes about Ruth’s battle with cancer.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="36">
    <dates>
      <start>8/2/16</start>
      <end>9/15/17</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook contains drawings from many parks throughout New York City. The journal entries continue to document Ruth’s battle with cancer and her passing in 2017.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="37">
    <dates>
      <start>9/19/17</start>
      <end>5/4/18</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>
      <p>This sketchbook consists mostly of journal entries discussing therapy and dealing with Ruth’s passing, both logistically and emotionally.</p>
      <p>The drawings in the sketchbook depict parks and people around New York City. There are also a few drawings of Ai Weiwei and his work Good Fences Make Good Neighbors beneath the arch in Washington Square Park.</p>
    </comment>
  </book>

  <book number="38">
    <dates>
      <start>5/8/18</start>
      <end>6/25/18</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook has many drawings from Paris and Père-Lachaise Cemetery, including a series of sketches of people on their phones. It contains very few journal entries.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="39">
    <dates>
      <start>6/26/18</start>
      <end>6/4/19</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook consists mostly of drawings of parks in NYC and a few drawings from a short trip to Paris. This is soon after Ruth’s passing.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="40">
    <dates>
      <start>6/9/19</start>
      <end>6/20/21</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This journal consists mostly of sketches of people around NYC. There are also drawings and journal entries from a quick trip Keith took to Paris.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="41">
    <dates>
      <start>6/30/21</start>
      <end>12/31/22</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This sketchbook contains drawings and journal entries in New York. It includes sketches made in parks, as well as numerous drawings from 38 White Street depicting the furniture, plants, studio space, and everyday objects throughout the apartment.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="42">
    <dates>
      <start>1/11/23</start>
      <end>5/21/25</end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This is the last sketchbook Keith kept before he passed away. The journal entries are about his battle with cancer and the final drawings are of self-portraits made during the last months of his life.</comment>
  </book>

  <book number="43">
    <dates>
      <start></start>
      <end></end>
    </dates>
    <comment>This journal was found in Keith and Ruth’s apartment in Paris.</comment>
  </book>

</books>